Hi. Before you get into the reading material for this case study, here's a super quick introduction to help you navigate Flexy.
Flexy is a dummy product built as a pilot MVP for ComEd.
ComEd is an electricity supply company covering the north of Illinois.
ComEd already offers an hourly dynamic tariff to around thirty-eight thousand customers and will soon start supplying time of use tariff as well.
Households, however, express anxiety around these tariffs and are unsure about how to avoid higher electricity bills.
Funny thing is that most households in the US already have a smart meter as well.
With this case study, I have focused on establishing viability of most of the features necessary for a product like Flexy to exist.
First one was the ability to fetch the live prices from ComEd directly.
Next one was the ability to control EVs regardless of their brand or the brand of their charger, and that was done using the Smartcar API.
And the last is the ability to fetch consumption data from the smart meters of households.
As you go through this case study, you can dive into Flexy's competition, go-to-market strategy and prioritized roadmap.